[Music]
thank you
can you believe it it's happened after
ever since I started YouTube I've been
asked to join the hermitcraft server and
it's finally happened I got an
invitation a couple of months ago and I
accepted that now means that I am part
of two smps which is going to be very
difficult on the workload side but I am
so in over my head I'm excited I'm happy
but
these guys are the real deal these guys
know Minecraft your guy you guys are
gonna be absolutely astounded by the
level of incompetency that I have when
it comes to this game part of the reason
that I made the Evo server which is
exploring the old editions of Minecraft
is because that's where I'm at home
because I sort of started my Minecraft
life playing the game in those versions
and as soon as creative became more
prevalent and I got into building I
actually dropped survival Minecraft all
together meaning my knowledge of
anything beyond 1.7 is is non-existent
so I'm gonna learn a lot I'm gonna learn
a lot about the technical side of things
I'm gonna learn a lot about the new
blocks I mean things like brewing and
chanting all that kind of stuff is a new
thing to me so
you guys are gonna have to be a bit
patient with me when it comes to this
sort of stuff
so this is sort of the island and I
haven't yet explained what's going on in
this season of hermitcraft and it's
pretty exciting we're going to need an
awful lot of materials because I've had
a little while to plan this I have
actually come up with the location that
I want to go so first of all what is
hermitcraft well it's basically
Minecraft with friends in in a nutshell
we're all going to be playing on the
same server however there is a few
special things about this series that
I'm gonna go over but we've actually got
to travel to the main island and it's
quite a long boat Journey so while I
sail over there I've made a little
infographic to explain exactly how this
series works for anyone that's a little
bit confused perhaps about what's going
to be going on so here we go
this is the season six hermitcraft map
and as you can see there's one big
island and this is where everything is
going to be happening most people will
be living on this island fairly close
together and other people may be close
by so they don't miss out on the action
the idea is that this is the central
point of this season and on this island
it's separated into different segments
and if you settle in one of these biomes
or in one of these borders you're
supposed to build in a different theme
meaning that you follow the block
palette and try and match the General
Building style that's going on so that
we have very distinct lands throughout
the island for example if you settle in
the top of the island that is the
Fantasy Realm so you might want to build
sort of Elven style or something like
that there's Aqua Town where you'll
probably build underwater there's Pirate
Land there's a shopping district
futuristic modern medieval and
Industrial now all of these cover most
of the building styles that I know the
one that I'm least confident in I would
say would be futuristic and that's where
I'm probably going to settle in the
north of the futuristic land in the
water so I can try out a style that I'm
not particularly strong at But as time
goes on we're going to go and explore
the other areas and build various
different things and it's very exciting
as everyone will have different bases
and different builds throughout the
island and it should be really cool
foreign I like this guy I'm not at the
base yet I'm not exactly where I want to
be but I think I'm on the island it's
kind of hard to know where to go but
then I just found this and this I don't
know why it's made me so happy it's so
funny
I I like you okay we are definitely in
the middle of the island I believe this
is kind of near Aqua Town so the map is
kind of hard to follow when you're
actually here my Center direction is not
too great but I know that the place that
I want to settle is over in the
futuristic area I have been sort of
dabbling with a few ideas if you guys
want to see me settle in another area
now is definitely the time to leave a
comment not before not after I've
already settled and made a load of stuff
but I do plan on sort of going around
and building different things I'm not
I'm not entirely set on it but because
this is the 1.13 update I want to spend
a lot of time in the ocean itself and
doing a lot of water related building
and I think that would be a lot of fun
so here is my area now I've already had
a conversation with my neighbor because
I actually claimed this area ahead of
time
and someone else had already claimed
pretty much exactly the same area
and that would be biffer who has made a
little cave up there as I can see so
this is the edge of the futuristic area
that I was going for I've got a few
build ideas but I don't want to share
them just yet just in case they don't
happen
now what we need to find is a sunken
ship because I've had a really good idea
on how to make a starter base in a very
very cheap way and no I'm not going to
be doing a dirt Hut unfortunately I know
that many people would love to have seen
me make a dirt Hut in my first ever
episode of hermitcraft but we're not
going to we're going to be doing
something a little bit more creative
than just a dirt Hut but first we need
to kind of find this ship and I can't
see it anywhere see if we can find ah
there it is there it is I knew that
there was one around here I just
couldn't find it so this is the ship
that we are going to be claiming as our
own and it's right next to a Chasm oh
how fantastic so this little canyon here
is going to no no no no no there's
bubbles in there I don't want to get
dragged down we're gonna have to be
really clever about this because one
little dive down here is all it takes
for my bubbles to deplete completely so
this is going to be where we call home
but before we can do anything we're
probably gonna need a bit more sand the
great thing about the technique that I'm
going to be doing is that I genuinely
don't need any decent tools whatsoever
to be able to do it I just is that
another ship over there I can kind of
see the outline of something but it's
kind of far away so we'll leave that for
now I need lots of sand because I'm
gonna need some glass and I'm gonna need
lots of sand itself
hopefully that's all we need I can't
believe we've only been on the server a
few minutes and we're already chock full
of stuff now the main thing that I need
to find actually is a bunch of turtles
because if I can make a turtle helmet
that's going to give me the extra 10
seconds I need underwater because it
gives you water breathing unfortunately
I haven't seen many turtles at all I
think they might spawn only in certain
parts of the ocean maybe only in warm
water and this is cold water you can
tell by the color of it
one thing that I'm a little bit worried
about are the amount of bubbles that
there are look at this it's just free
fish
and if you go across this it's a bit
dangerous because those bubbles will
drag my boat down so I've got to be
careful and make sure I don't AFK on
those things and I've got to take care
of these fellas these are going to
interrupt my life as well I don't think
he can get me I think I'm pretty safe
do they drop they drop useful stuff I
think
what he's useless oh dear it seems like
there's quite a lot of these drowned
around at least they can't touch me
while I'm here can they actually maybe
if I just let him no I I don't I
literally don't think he can touch me at
all so what I'm gonna have to do is go
over to the ship where this is I'm gonna
have to make a little dirt Tower
unfortunately
because I need a little platform for
this to work
so we're gonna go straight up
this is how this is gonna work so I need
to make sure I make this the the right
size I went AFK for a few minutes and I
come back and I think I'm surrounded you
can't see them
oh but they're definitely there look
there he is I don't think he can get me
while I'm out of the water which seems
like a bit of a FL oh my goodness
there's so many of them I can't I can't
get them either this might seriously be
a problem just as I kill one another one
floats to the surface and that's not an
exaggeration are they spawning around my
ship because if that's the case we might
struggle to make this so I think I need
to act quickly otherwise these guys are
gonna spawn around really fast
I haven't actually got a lot of
resources now that I I think of it so I
need to be quick about this but I
actually need to make a little trip down
there because I need to make sure for
this to work it needs to be flat down
here needs to be completely flat and
that's going to be much harder than I
thought
oh no this isn't going to work is it
I have to make
I'm gonna have to make several trips
just to get this flat one block at a
time
this isn't going to be good this is
going to take a long time and I'm
probably going to drown this is a little
bit tricky to set up but once it's
actually done this should work a treat
think I'm gonna have to destroy all of
these blocks as well with the fences and
stuff I need it completely flat
ah no
no ah this is so
it's every step of the way I'm getting
mauled by these guys
thankfully they're not that smart
they're like kind of head banging
towards me like it looks like they're
dancing
rock out rock out we are the drown
all right down we go again
couple more Dives and we'll be
completely finished well not completely
finished we'll be ready to start
actually working on this thing now the
reason I need it to be completely flat
is because we're going to sink some sand
onto this it should make sense in no
time at all maybe one more dive and
we'll be good to go
so while I've been diving down I've been
leaving this to smelt me some glass
because that's what we're going to need
but first I need to make myself a bigger
dirt platform on how this is going to
work out so this is a pretty creative
way I think
um to make an underwater dome but I'm
actually gonna have to destroy what I've
bye bed
my bed
that's gonna be our Circle there so
we've got this very very I I don't think
I've ever made such an ugly platform
made out of various different hey my
bed's back
I'll have to get that later
if for some reason items sink all the
way to the bottom and then just float up
again
it's amazing right so this one is our
center block
so if I'm correct and I'm not usually we
need to make
three blocks now I need to make sure
that this Dome
is gonna work so I actually need to make
it one smaller than the final product
okay so as it stands this is the current
sphere although because it's so small it
won't really look too spherical
so as this Falls the idea is that it
will fall exactly in this shape that
I've made here and in order to make it
more spherical I'm gonna have to take a
few Liberties so I think I'm probably
gonna have to leave it at that it will
look a bit better because the glass is
going to go on the top of this so this
is only the interior space so imagine
that this sand is air once it falls down
the glass is going to be placed on top
of this like so underwater these drowned
man I think these drowned really are
spawning very close to me or do they
just spawn in the ocean in general I'm
so lucky that they're pretty bad I
haven't come across any with a trident
yet so I'm not too worried at the moment
oh no it's a little limp fella let me
get this dirt block and then we can
fight okay come on little fella
oh ow no no Trident man ah that just
bounced off me
um okay I might be in trouble here I
might oh I might be in serious trouble
here
there's a trident man coming for me
I think a lot of people that are into
hermitcraft will be like why haven't you
got any armor because I want to make a
house first
make a beeline for the boat make a
beeline for the boat I don't think he
can get me ow
those tridents really hurt
ah no no don't you dare
don't you dare
this is not good this is not good
this is terrifying this is genuinely
terrifying I think I should play it safe
and maybe sleep for the night I really
hope that this guy under here drops a
trident because I haven't actually
played with the Trident very much
let's go what
he's vanished
they've gone oh no they haven't where is
where is he oh he's there oh no no no no
no no no no
you monster
at least my stuff's gonna come back to
the surface Now where's the sword all
I've got to get is my sword man that's
really gone all over the place
maybe I can just take the stone sword
and go for them
where are they where are they
where is he I can't see him he's there
oh this is not fair
this is ridiculous
okay I actually I see him this time
let's go straight for him don't even
don't even let him I got him
this is actually awful these are no
problem these guys are not a problem
whatsoever
but these these Trident fellas oh my
goodness now did he actually drop a
trident that I can pick up that's what I
want to know
is that can I not do anything with that
I don't know how it works that looks
like I can pick it up but I don't think
I can once we get to the bottom of this
pillar we can release the sand
and then we can actually get on with
this episode
I can hear one please don't be a trident
fella
[Music]
all right last little bit last little
bit
all right that's flat flat enough for me
to work with anyway
and then we can release it
hopefully
down it goes
bit by bit now as it falls it should
fall directly into place
oh no no no no no no no no no no no no
no no
you are joking
I've never seen such a sad sight in my
life
what's happened is the sand has fallen
on slabs
and it's it's broken oh you can see
where exactly where it was this is a
nightmare and now there's another
drowned after me somewhere
oh no
okay I have finally done it I've gone
down and changed everything so it now
should just be a case of letting it all
drop into place
there it goes
no disasters
oh my goodness this was I've now learned
quite a few things I I mean I kind of
knew that sand broke on slabs but I just
didn't realize there was so many down
there
it looks like everything is correctly
falling into place
now hopefully there's no drown down here
again
because they are absolute nightmare okay
so all we got to do is take our glass
and we build
the the sphere around it oh no so we
just make our way around placing the
glass around the perfect sphere that we
made out of sand or it's not actually a
perfect sphere all we got to do is fix
up the top and leave a hole in the
middle that's the main thing leaving a
hole in the middle one two three oh
we're one block short okay so I haven't
actually tested this
but
the theory should hold
let's I think we should just go for it
okay
this is everyone we're going for it dive
down as fast as we can
ah
and then we Dig Down
three
and then we make that yes
we made it and then all we got to do is
remove the sand from inside this glass
Dome and we have ourselves
a little air bubble
this is brilliant now I've shown this on
a video before but I've never actually
done it in survival myself I just made
sure that the actual technique worked
and it's actually done pretty well and
to be honest with you if it wasn't for
all those drowned mobs everywhere
I think this would have been a really
really quick way to do it so we're gonna
do now is remove that and we've done it
oh this is beautiful this is actually
wonderful
we're gonna have to delete all that mess
up there
I need a way out
I need a way out that is for sure
I need a way out but for the time being
we can work with what we've got so
underneath here
is what we're going to work on next so
we're just going to fill this with sand
and start clearing out this shipwreck
and then we're gonna have a place to
make a base oh this is so cool I
absolutely love this I have definitely
made the right decision making an
underwater base
this is gonna be so cool we've got a lot
of work to do now to make this livable
the problem is we've got to clear out
the water from all of these little nooks
and crannies because all of this is like
upside down staircases and you can
actually put water in them now
I the thing is I actually genuinely feel
like I'm physically
shoveling out water with this bucket it
really does feel like it I guess I guess
that's kind of realistic in a way but
it's taking a very long time
hold on
I didn't know that this went round chest
now obviously because this is
whoa
this was a gold mine oh my goodness
how many iron one two three four five
six seven eight eight ingots
five emeralds a bottle of enchanting
loads of iron nuggets
two gold ingots and some lapis
that's incredible now why is that got
water around it there we go it takes a
seriously long time to get anything out
of here because the water is so
persistent I really need like 10 empty
buckets to make any dent in this there
we go I think that's it I think that's
the entire thing cleared out we don't
have a lot of space here that's for sure
how do we make this it maybe we can make
a way in with signs yes they still do
block air but only if you don't place
them on a full block of water so we can
go in and out of our base now as we
please look at that not too shabby I
mean it doesn't look like the best thing
in the world but you know what I'm
pretty happy with it because that's all
we need for the time being I know that
it is it has a long way to go it has a
long way to go and this is only a
temporary base but boy I have definitely
learned my lesson just make a dirt house
just make a dirt House Green don't do
this to yourself do you know how long I
I don't I kind of don't want to admit
how long I've spent on this if I'm being
honest
I don't want to admit it I can't get
over how beautiful this is
now is there actually anything here that
I can utilize oh my goodness it actually
goes in
leave that's where that noise was coming
from okay so I think there's a little
room down here with a with a little
drowning
right there
so we can go ahead and get him and we
actually have another extra room that we
can empty out this is brilliant
there we go
there's nothing oh oh there is something
in the chest
we're actually pretty good on space I
thought this was going to be way more
cramped in than it was well then it is I
thought this was going to be really
really tight it is a little bit tight
but we're actually discovering more and
more rooms as we go along I got to admit
this is a pretty cool first base though
as far as as far as dirt houses go
this one's pretty cool I was seriously
hoping for a full sized one but I'm
gonna have to settle for the half size
and to be honest with you
I'm not too I'm not too upset because
well this took a really really long time
to sort out like we're talking in excess
of an hour and a half
just to get to this point here and I'm
not sure I can take it anymore so this
is pretty cool now we need to go and
actually get ourselves some resources as
we have a base of operations but there
is a buried treasure map which I am
struggling to resist the urge
if I look at it I can see the treasure
map I might go and get that another time
so maybe we'll keep that for later it
doesn't have to be where we sort of
settle indefinitely we can keep it
simple for the time being I'm I'm easy
going I'd love to hear what you guys
think there's probably one thing that
you should know about me is that I'm not
like the other Hermits you see I'm a
little bit different I don't do things
perhaps the most efficiently or the best
way my goal here is to have as much fun
as possible okay I I do build a lot
that's true but I mainly want to have
the best time that I possibly can on
this server and I don't yet know what
that means exactly
it could mean very many things so let's
try and head down into a cavern let's
ditch some of our stuff and head down
into a cavern I haven't actually got
much food so this is probably a terrible
idea but we're gonna go anyway
what's that old saying
don't dig straight down
I think we can forget about that
can we see anything useful is there any
cave systems don't want to go too far
look there's my boat my boats look
sagged
well here is this is this is the ravine
doesn't seem to be much here apart from
some seagrass and some magma box which
we are going to collect
right now though I want to kind of focus
on finding some diamonds and this is
actually a pretty good place to start
because this here on this is y13
more commonly known as Diamond level so
as long as we sort of start strip mining
we should find some stuff to kind of
give you an idea of just how far removed
I am from being up to date on Minecraft
let alone hermitcraft just Minecraft
this is the first time I'm using dual
wielding that's how like old school of a
player I am and just how long I've been
building for I've never properly used
dual wielding I mean I could have many
times I just I guess I just don't find
it that enjoyable I get a bit confused I
don't know I'm just I'm just a bit
rubbish basically
now I've not done too badly for myself I
have not found a single Diamond yet I've
got a stack of lapis and a stack of iron
ore exactly to the Mark I might add so I
need to make myself a few more pickaxes
because we need diamonds and the reason
we need diamonds is because I don't want
to be left behind I don't want to be the
new hermit that doesn't know what
they're doing I want Enchanted stuff
because from what I can tell almost
every single person gets loads of
diamonds has entire Diamond gear and has
basically built an entire city in their
first episode and I don't wanna I don't
want to get left behind
so I've actually done a fair amount
today and I'm still not finished there's
something that I desperately want to do
but I haven't got the things that I need
yet I actually need to go to the nether
I've done a lot of resource getting look
at all this iron I have already spent my
diamonds on these pitiful tools I did so
much mining but didn't get anywhere so
let's take a look at my ship I have
actually made this as thin as it can
possibly get utilized as much space as I
can and this is the result I think I've
done pretty well you can tell that this
is really really pushing the limits with
all of these staircases and slabs and
I've even used some trap doors to try
and make it look a bit more homely this
is my little area down here and the
reason I've put a door here is what I
don't really want people going down here
and two it's not really in the ship
theme so this is actually the bottom of
the ship as it sits right now and I've
just been digging this out because this
is where I need to put the nether port
bottle but I need to go and get the
obsidian in order to do that
I've got my hands on 14 obsidian and
that's it we are going to
the nether okay we're ready
let's go I desperately do not want to
lose my levels it's taken me a long time
to get to this point
and we're here might as well take some
mushrooms
what I actually came to get my hands on
wasn't caught but we will need to strip
that out
it's actually Soul Sand I need Soul Sand
in order to do what I'm hoping to do
how did I get this Soul Sand so easy
where did this come from no seriously I
I didn't mind this
just what's going on here
I just came through the Nether and
there's five Soul Sand in my in my hand
I didn't mine it
what on Earth
I guess that's one of life's great
Mysteries but seriously
you saw it from start to finish didn't
have any whenever I've built something
in Minecraft I've always taken for
granted
how hard it is
to get Quartz or how much of a grind it
is to get caught I always use it because
it's one of the best white blocks and
it's got uh the slabs and staircases and
stuff but I've not really considered
enough how much of a pain it is to get
I honestly yeah I really should take
more care because grinding this one out
not not great but hopefully over time if
we just visit here every now and again
we will get what we need in the quartz
Department I'm gonna be needing a lot of
concrete a lot of concrete a lot of
quartz a lot of white blocks a lot of
dyes it's gonna be very very interesting
but that's all I actually needed to get
from the nether
there's something I've desperately want
to try
wait a second
oh no
I've ended up in someone else's base
what's going on here
there's a chicken farmer oh my goodness
what on Earth
this is what I'm talking about I'm in
way over my head here they've already
got a massive chicken farm going on
where are you where am I
oh
the retin hole I'm guessing that's
Rendog he's part of the hermit thank
goodness I brought a boat with me I'm
not entirely sure where I am did that
just vanish oh my boat's back in my hand
um so we're not actually anywhere near
our base right now we need to head this
way
and I think over to the right
what on Earth is this who is that what's
going on there's already so much stuff
happening is someone building a boat
it's only episode one calm down I just
took that is zombie Clio I just took
over a shipwreck and you're already
building a boat
uh I'm I'm in way over my head on this
series
actually while we're here on the way
back we're actually not too far away our
base is just over there the sunken ship
is just over there now I know that it's
not modern that's the main thing it is
not modern in the slightest but we are
close to Pirate Island which is here
this is where good times with scar is
building and as you can see he's already
started Landscaping the entire area
thought we could just take a little
little look around while we're here
so lots of cobblestone lots of sandstone
I mean it doesn't actually take you long
to get your hands on this stuff so this
probably didn't take him too long he's
actually down there so I wonder what
he's actually gone and made it's pretty
cool but he's only a few uh he's only a
few hundred blocks away from me like a
short boat journey and he would run
straight into me I have no idea how you
get into his base he hasn't hidden it
already have you
oh he's actually living in a cave right
now
[Laughter]
he just drowned in front of her he was
right there looking at us
I was just visiting the base and I
thought it was really cool
and he was just okay look at this good
guy Green picking up someone's stuff
isn't that nice look at this he ended up
when he died he went all the way back to
spawn look at that good guy green just
put his stuff in a chest for him
now that's super out of character for me
as everyone knows because this is
slightly different from the Evo server
if you guys watch my Minecraft evolution
series you guys know I am a troublemaker
a big troublemaker and it's not that I'm
not going to cause Mayhem I definitely
am I just I'm the newcomer here these
guys will know each other I don't know
them I don't want to come rushing in and
just causing an absolute scene we gotta
ease them into it okay we've got to ease
them into the Mayhem
there we go just so that he knows
exactly where I stand on these matters
here's your stuff from Good Guy green
who won't prank you one day
there we go I'll just leave that where
it is let's head on back to the base
because it's one thing I want to try
before we head off and next episode I'm
going to be looking at trying
desperately to get my hands on a turtle
helmet which means getting scooped now
the way I do that is I have to look
after baby turtles until they become big
turtles and that's not as easy as it
sounds or it's laborious at any rate so
that's going to take some time
but for now we've got ourselves settled
we've got a huge amount of stuff I've
been mining for hours and we've got
ourselves half a shipwreck that one day
we're gonna turn into a modern
futuristic Masterpiece and down we go
could I save it can you save it if I
push it can I save it no bye bye
I think throughout this series we're
gonna have a lot of boats down there at
some point
oh home sweet home okay so what I wanted
to do is no easy task you see what I
want to do is have an open entrance of
water and that is tough okay really
tough because the water physics do not
want to work in my favor ever so we're
just gonna make something really rough
at the moment a proof of concept here
so the main thing is we don't want to
have too much water in here we just want
a quick entrance and exit so the main
thing is if we hop out here we want to
create sort of a lip that goes across
like this
and then that leaves us or actually I
might need to create a little bit more
if I create a little bit of a
thing here because we want this to be
air to begin with hopefully this will
work out
and then we take this away
oh that's brilliant I think that's I
think that is roughly what we want we
just want a big wall of water
now here's the tricky bit
we're gonna have to get rid of this
stuff and we want to add in Soul Sand
because Soul Sand gives off bubbles that
go up so I think you might have worked
out where this is going if you just give
me a second all I need to do now is fill
in the water at this point I could take
water from what
I thought I could take water from
anywhere
that might be a little bug
so the idea is all we got to do now is
make a quick boat okay so I got I got my
boat
this is gonna if this works I'm gonna be
so pleased
so this is our little entrance
we go out
what what happened oh I hit the ceiling
oh no I didn't think this through I need
I'm too far over
that's not good okay so we know that it
roughly Works we're gonna have to try
widen this out okay we got a seriously
good looking bubble column going on so
in theory we take the boat
we take the boat out like so
oh this is brilliant
look at that
look at that absolutely perfect
and you know what we can actually turn
that off at some point if we like get
ourselves loads of Pistons we can make
that be toggleable so we can like have a
little underwater
launch pad essentially which is
brilliant so I think that's probably
where I'm going to have to end my first
ever episode of hermitcraft Now this one
has been a little longer than I usually
would make my videos and that's because
I actually have to go away for four days
I've really really enjoyed making this
first ever episode I really have maybe
it's just the excitement of the new uh
the new version but this is gonna be so
much fun I can't wait to see what we do
I've got some big plans and I'm not
gonna spoil them all now so this really
really came at a bad time because I just
want to play more and I want to upload a
bit more regularly than once a week so
unfortunately it will be a little bit of
a wait before number two comes out but
hopefully I won't be too far behind I
bet when I get back everyone will have
already basically completed the game
it'll all be that the entire Island will
be colonized and full of buildings left
right and Center which I think would be
quite funny anyway
thank you very much for watching
everyone that's it from me if you did
like this please leave a like and leave
me a comment telling me what you think
do you think I should stay in the
futuristic Zone do you think I should go
somewhere else any info at all is a
brilliant idea so thank you thank you
thank you thank you thank you and good
bye
[Music]